Hello, good afternoon, my name is Daniel Bahr and I am the author of the design book
in which at the tiff coachers it is a great pleasure to be able to greet you this afternoon at
the celebration of earth day in costa rica eduardo thanks for giving me the
opportunity to contribute this short video
Eduardo has asked me to talk a little about the subject that there is a great
growing movement in the world that is dedicating itself to creating cultures
regenerative that are very elegantly adapted to the conditions
unique cultural bios of your place and to briefly summarize what
we're talking like we're talking about
the regeneration of this bill read graph from 2006 offers us a way
a path from business is yuyo towards the body also all green that
is a bit better but still harm t to a sustainable extent than in this
frame originates as the point of doing no more damage but as this is no longer
enough as we have done so much damage in the history of mankind and its
relationship with nature through the last five thousand to eight thousand
years with the invention of agriculture and land use change and that
we have bare the earth an 9.8 billion trees have been cut down
name of trees of forest hectares have been cut in the last
five thousand years by man then it is necessary to create something more
which is to restore ecosystems and it is a pleasure to know that the 1 is reacting
and in the 20s and 130s the decade for ecosystem restoration has been declared
but if we do not make one more change of the restorative design of only
restore and systems stuff and realize we don't have to do this
reconciliatory step of creating from a change of culture a change of
worldview thinking that again includes humanity within the
nature that we finally realize that as biological living beings we are
nature and we are able to create conducive conditions for life in
an evolutionary step that we finally
we realize that in competition it is only part of the regulation and
that collaboration has largely created a much more complex living world
through millions of years of the evolution of life and like us
We ourselves have done so much damage to this web of life, now it is our turn to create
cultures that are truly mature and mature members of this community of the
life I think this is already asking for
very
In many ways, London has formed the extinct rebellion that is
growing up to the level of the world in the movement fried wife of grita terna
is taking school children to the streets every Friday to ask for a
deeper shift towards a reaction to climate change that already has to be
so profound that it is truly a redesign of the human presence in the
planet and this is what it is all about and I am super happy that my book design edition
art scouters that was published in 2016 has been part of this change of
consciousness and I have just returned from Brazil where we have launched
regenerative cultures in Portuguese and by the end of this year there will also be
launch the book in Spanish Costa Rica is a leading country in
leadership in this whole movement the work he has done was very read with the
chapter institute and other partners such as guy education institute or cyber and in
several others is to create a network at the local and global level to strengthen this movement
to create regenerative cultures and economies to create a new
human presence on the planet through regenerative development at the
bioregional and it is a great pleasure to collaborate with you in Costa Rica and
I am doing my thing here on the island of Mallorca in Spain and every day there are more
people who are moving or moving this issue of active regional development
bioregional as a redesign of the human presence on the planet and
important of degenerative cultures that are diverse as life and have to
be highly adapted to the unique conditions of your place and
with this we create a diverse world but alienated to create regenerative futures
for all life and all future generations of our species
of our children and of our grandchildren and great-grandchildren then
congratulations on jacques red creating a regeneration day and if we get it right
the next decade is going to be the decade of ecosystem restoration and this
century is going to be the century of regeneration of the earth and
humanity thank you very much and have a good afternoon and see you soon
in Costa Rica